firetalk.com 2010-04-21

# Paltalk Privacy Policy

Paltalk is committed to protecting your privacy. We want you to feel free to express yourself within the Paltalk community, and are committed to ensuring that you are in control of what you share with the rest of the community, and with Paltalk. 

**_Information Collection & Use_**

**_Registration_**  
In order to use Paltalk, you must first complete the registration form. During registration you are required to give contact information such as your email address. We use this information to contact you about services on our site in which you have expressed interest. Please see below for Information and Sharing Disclosure. 

**_Communications from the Site_**

  * _Special Offers and Updates_  
We will occasionally send you information on products, services, special deals, or promotions. Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out.” 
  * _Newsletters_  
If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter, we will use your email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see the “Choice and Opt-out” section. 
  * _Service-related Announcements_  
We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account. 
  * _Customer Service_  
Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes. 
  * _Profile_  
We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, to create a “profile” of your preferences. We tie your personally identifiable information, and your purchasing history, to information in the profile, in order to provide tailored promotions and marketing offers and to improve the content of the site for you. We do not share your profile with other third parties without your consent. 

Paltalk is the sole owner of the information collected on Paltalk.com. Paltalk collects personally identifiable information from our users at several different points on our Web site or through our downloaded software. 

  * _Orders_  
If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and billing address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). 

We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. We will use this information to contact you and confirm your orders. 

**_Uses of Information_**  
Paltalk's primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with a customized experience on Paltalk and through our partners. This includes personalization services, interactive communications, and many other types of services, most of which are completely free to you. In order to provide services free of charge, we display advertisements and encourage your participation. By knowing a little about you, Paltalk is able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content, and hence better service, to you. 

In our role of delivering targeted advertisements, Paltalk plays the middleman. Advertisers give us advertisements and tell us the type of audience they want to reach (for example, males over 35 years old). Paltalk displays the advertisement to users meeting the specified criteria. In this process, the advertiser never has access to individual user information. This kind of advertisement targeting is done with banner ads as well as promotional email through Paltalk and its affiliates. You will only receive special offers via email from Paltalk if you have indicated in your account preferences, or at some other time, that you would like to receive them. 

**_Personally identifiable information:_**

  * _Agents_   
We use outside credit card processing companies to bill you for Paltalk services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes.   
We use outside email delivery systems to contact you and provide you with pertinent information via email. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes. 
  * _Advertising_   
We use third-party advertising companies and advertising networks to serve ads to you on our behalf when you visit our Web site.  These companies may use information (not including personal information such as your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. 
  * _Legal Disclaimer_   
We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site. 

_**Choice/Opt-out**_

We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. 

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or visiting [http://register.paltalk.com/reg/ControllerServlet?RequestId=Register.ShowOptout&src=paltalk](http://register.paltalk.com/reg/ControllerServlet?RequestId=Register.ShowOptout&src=paltalk). You may also contact us at: 

Paltalk.com  
PO Box 7528,  
New York, NY 10116-7481

Or, please contact our helpful customer support staff online. On the Paltalk buddy list window, click Groups, then Paltalk Help Groups. 

**_Log Files_**  
As is true of most Web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. 

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to administer the site and to track users' movements around the site. 

We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information except during special promotions such as free trials when subscription IP addresses are temporarily tied to personally identifiable information. 

**_Cookies_**  
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use session ID cookies on this site to maintain your subscription and maintain your account. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. 

**_Clear Gifs_**  
We employ a software technology called clear gifs that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information. 

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see “Choice and Opt-out.” 

**_Third Party Advertisers_**  
The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to users by a Paltalk proprietary ad serving system. We share Web site usage information about users with reputable third party ad networks for the purpose of targeting our banner advertisements on Paltalk software. 

We use third-party advertising companies and advertising networks to serve ads to you on our behalf when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including personal information such as your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. 

**_Links to Other Sites_**  
Paltalk contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Paltalk. Please be aware that we, Paltalk, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. 

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. 

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by Paltalk. 

By visiting this Site, all visitors consent to the collection, maintenance, and processing of their personal and non-personal information in the United States. 

**_Paltalk Discussion Rooms_**  
If you use a discussion room on Paltalk, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. 

**_Access to Personally Identifiable Information_**  
If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, delete or deactivate it by making the change on [http://my.paltalk.com](http://my.paltalk.com/) or by contacting our helpful customer support staff online by clicking Groups on the Paltalk buddy list window, then Paltalk Help. 

_**Security**_

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information such as credit card numbers on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Finally, the servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment. 

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact our helpful customer support staff online. On the Paltalk buddy list window, click Groups, then Paltalk Help Groups. 

**_Business Transitions_**  
In the event Paltalk goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. 

**_Changes in this Privacy Statement_**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. 

This statement reflects the privacy policy of Paltalk with respect to the Web site located at www.Paltalk.com (the “Site”). This statement is intended to inform casual visitors of Paltalk, and visitors who participate in Paltalk, of the data collection and use practices of the Site. Amendments to this statement will be posted at this URL and will be effective when posted. Your continued use of this Site following the posting of any amendment, modification, or change shall constitute your acceptance thereof except if your personally identifiable information will be used in a materially different manner. 

**_Contact Us_**  
If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

Paltalk.com  
PO Box 7528,  
New York, NY 10116-7481

Or, by visiting our helpful customer support staff online, on the Paltalk buddy list window, click Groups, then Paltalk Help Groups. 

**::Top::**
